星空字幕组
SSK•FanSub
关注新浪微博
@SSK字幕组
几年前
在南极洲
Antarctica.
生物极难生存
An inhospitable wasteland.
但即使在这地球最严寒的一端
But even here, on the Earth's frozen bottom,
仍有生命存在
we find life.
且不是平凡的生命
And not just any life.
而是企鹅
Penguins.
它们欢乐嬉戏 蹒跚而行
Joyous, frolicking, waddling,
可爱极了
cute and cuddly life.
看 它们毛茸茸的肚子前后相碰
Look at them tumbling onto their chubby bum-bums.
谁会想到这些活泼雪白的家伙
Who could take these frisky little snow clowns...
等等 有人知道我们要去哪么
Seriously? Does anyone even know where we're marching to?
-有什么关系呢 -我从不问东问西的
- Who cares? - I question nothing.
-我也是 -我也是
- Me, too. - Me, too.
好吧 那我们就飞到最前面去
Well, fine! We'll just fly
看看我们到底要去哪里
to the front of the line and see for ourselves.
科沃斯基 瑞哥 开启空中探险模式
Kowalski! Rico! Engage aerial surveillance.
走吧 来啊 快点
Here we go! Doing it! Come on!
老大 我们好像不能飞
Skipper, we appear to be flightless.
那这是用来干什么的
Well, what's the point of these?
哇 我喜欢 可以当做我们的招牌动作
Whoa! I like it! Hey, this could be our thing!
叫什么呢 就叫击掌好了
What are we gonna call it? Let's call it the... "High one."
嘿 你们看见了么 那个蛋滚走了 谁去把它找回来
Hey! Anybody see that? That's an egg! Is someone gonna go get it?
-我们不能那么做 -为什么
- We can't do that. - Why not?
外面的世界很危险的 我们只是企鹅
Well, it's a dangerous world out there, and we're just penguins.
负责可爱就好
You know, nothing but cute and cuddly.
要不然为什么
Yeah. Why do you think
总有人在拍我们
there are always documentary crews filming us?
安啦 孩子们
Well, sorry, kid. You know,
我们每年都会遗失一些没出生的宝宝 自然规则而已
we lose a few eggs every year. It's just nature.
好吧 自然规律 说得好像有道理
Oh, right, nature. I guess that makes sense, but...
但是
something...
骨子里总有一些声音告诉我
something deep down in my
这一点也不合常理
gut tells me that it makes no sense at all.
我决定了 我要反对自然规律
You know what? I reject nature!
谁要和我一起
Who's with me?!
那是艘废弃的船 没有人能活着从那里走出来
The old ship. No one's ever returned from there alive.
怎么会 下面就有一只鸟 看起来很悠闲
Relax, Kowalski. There's a bird down there now. Look, he's fine.
豹斑海豹 大自然的毒蛇
Leopard seals... nature's snakes.
大自然的毒蛇不是蛇么
Aren't snakes nature's snakes?
我怎么会知道 我天天住在这冻原里
How should I know? I live on the flipping frozen tundra.
它们要吃那个蛋 快想办法让我下去 快
They're going for the egg! Give me a way down there, ASAP!
我们现在需要做的就是
All one would have to do
找到足足300英尺高的海草 然后
is collect 300 feet of kelp, dry it in the...
弱小又无助 这些企鹅宝宝冻坏了
Tiny and helpless, the baby penguins are frozen with fear.
它们知道要是掉下悬崖 会必死无疑
They know if they fall from this cliff, they will surely die.
甘特 推它们一下
Gunter, give them a shove.
我们用训练水母
...harnessing the jellyfish
的口令行事
we've trained to obey simple voice commands.
这才像话嘛
Now, that's more like it!
干得好 瑞克 别让他得逞
That-a-boy, Rico! Don't let him have it!
哇 这样就安全了
Okay. I guess that works.
快跳到高地方去
Get to high ground!
-哇哈 -成功了
- Boo-yah! - Success!
-我建议赶快发火 -别 再等一下
- I'd recommend firing it now. - Nope, hold on.
我们真的应该立刻开火
We really should fire it.
我还没有看见它的眼白
Not till we see the white of its eyes.
它们的眼睛都是纯黑的 只有很少的眼白 几乎没有
They're mostly pupil. Very little white. Almost none!
多少也该有一点吧
They got to have a little bit of white, right?
-没有又怎样 -如果它们只往一边看呢
- None whatsoever. - What if they look really far to the left?
开炮
Fire in the hole!
科斯基 分析一下状况
Kowalski, analysis?
我们真是酷毙了
We are really awesome at this.
兄弟们 成功了 任务达成
Boys, we did it! Mission accomplished!
嘿 我们真的成功了 击掌
Hey, hey, we can do our thing. High one!
棒
Yes!
我的错
My bad.
看 生命的奇迹
Look. It's... it's the miracle of birth.
这一刻 格外的美丽
A moment... of extraordinary beauty.
噢 好恶心 我嘴里全是黏液
Oh, that's disgusting! I think I have amniotic sac in my mouth!
哦
Whoa!
你们好 你们是我的家人么
Hello. Are you my family?
你没有家人 我们都活不长了 不好意思
You don't have a family, and we're all going to die. Sorry.
啥
What?
怎么了 我以为你们也是这个意思
What? I thought that was what we were all nodding about.
谁都不会死 我们都是你的家人 孩子
No one's gonna die! Know what you've got, kid?
你有我们 我们会一直在一起
You've got us. We've got each other.
我们就是一个家庭
And if that ain't a family, I don't know what is.
你真可爱
So adorable.
科沃斯基 我们的航程会怎样
Kowalski, what's our trajectory?
-95%的可能我们会死翘翘 -那5%的可能性呢
- 95% certain we're still doomed. - And the other five percent?
获得企鹅史上从未有过的探险和荣光
Adventure and glory like no penguins have ever seen before.
-就选它了 -我们要去哪里
- I'll take that action. - But where are we going?
未来 同志们
The future, boys.
辉煌的未来
Glorious future!
这破歌 吵的我都要吐了
That song! I swear it's gonna make me lose my salmon.
老大 声音越来越大了
Singing getting louder, Skipper!
动作加快 谁去把那个家伙的假发拿下来
Then move faster! Somebody get that wig off Private.
科沃斯基 报告状况
Kowalski, status report!
我受够这首歌了
I'm really getting tired of this song.
在马戏团最大的好处
Well, the best part of owning a
就是可以用大炮瞬间转移
circus is you can transport a cannon over state lines.
马达加斯加的企鹅
十年前的今天 你出生了
Ten years ago on this very day, a tiny egg hatched,
本字幕由 SSK字幕组 原创译制
仅供学习交流，严禁商业行为，转载请注明出处
版权归片方所有，请在24小时内删除
粉丝群：133235912   新浪微博：SSK字幕组
本字幕由 SSK字幕组 原创译制
仅供学习交流，严禁商业行为，转载请注明出处
版权归片方所有，请在24小时内删除
粉丝群：133235912   新浪微博：SSK字幕组
本字幕由 SSK字幕组 原创译制
仅供学习交流，严禁商业行为，转载请注明出处
版权归片方所有，请在24小时内删除
粉丝群：133235912   新浪微博：SSK字幕组
本字幕由 SSK字幕组 原创译制
仅供学习交流，严禁商业行为，转载请注明出处
版权归片方所有，请在24小时内删除
粉丝群：133235912   新浪微博：SSK字幕组
让我们这个家庭更加美好 所以今天 菜鸟
and our world got a little bit cuter. So tonight, Private,
翻译：梨叔  Reckless  JessieJ
我们一起
we celebrate your birthday
潜入诺克斯堡的黄金存放处来为你庆生
by infiltrating the United States gold depository at Fort Knox!
校对：冬可可   娄小胖  金刚妹
特效：CAS
-太酷炫了 -什么
- Splendid! - What?
压制：hhjie
同志们 在那了
There she is, boys.
那就是我们邪恶的欲望 唾手可得
The object of our unholy desire. The butter on our biscuit.
总监：Bezero
-同花顺 -老大
- The royal flush. - Skipper?
注意 不能随意打断别人讲话
Private, what's our rule about interrupting analogies?
-抱歉 你继续 -算了 不想说了 都怪菜鸟
- Sorry. Please continue. - The moment's gone. Private ruined it.
我们接近目标了
Sir, we're approaching our target.
但是 队长 我
But, Skipper, I really...
你在质疑我的领导能力么 菜鸟
Are you questioning my leadership, Private?
-没有 长官 -真可惜
- No, sir. - Too bad.
因为我只尊敬有胆量的士兵
'Cause I respect a soldier with some moxie.
真的可以吗 其实我觉得我们应该
Really? Then I really think we should...
哇 哇 哇 别马后炮了 乌鸦嘴
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Dial back the moxie, sass-mouth.
哦 你还是那么可爱
Oh, look at you. Still so adorable.
准备投弹
Fire in the hole!
睡觉时间
Night-night time.
啥
Wha...?
菜鸟 快点
Private, come on!
-请输入密码 -科沃斯基 你上
- Please enter pass code. - Kowalski, you're up.
-请输入密码 -瑞哥 声波入侵
- Please enter pass code. - Rico, sonic incursion device.
拜托 现在还有时间开玩笑吗
Oh, come on, you're kidding right?
老大 这是肯塔基州 他们都喜欢乡村乐
Kentucky, Skipper. They do love their Flatt and Scruggs.
所有人准许进入 快进来喝杯冰茶吧
Y'all come in now, y'hear? Have yourself a iced tea.
菜鸟 如果全世界的东西你都可以拥有
Private, if you could have anything you wanted
你选什么
in the whole wide world, what would it be?
老大 我想应该是
Well, gee, Skipper, I think to
成为队伍中得力的一员
be a meaningful and valued member of this team.
好吧 我们给你准备了别的
Well, we got you something else.
自动贩售机
A vending machine?
菜鸟 这可不是普通的自动贩售机
not just any vending machine, Private.
这是专门出售
The last remaining home
美国保姆政府家中常备的
in America's nanny state for those succulent
超级美味的膨化美食
but chemically hazardous bits of puffed heaven called...
芝士条
Cheezy Dibbles!
生日快乐 小傻瓜
Happy ding-dong birthday, you little scamp!
谢谢你
Thank you!
自己动手 丰衣足食
You mess with the bull, you're gonna get the horns, Private.
菜鸟 自己去拿礼物吧
Now, hit that machine and get your present.
我们入侵了全美安全系数最高的机构
We just broke into the most secure facility in North America.
你知道这意味着什么吗
You know what that means?
我们要被通缉
We're wanted criminals
在逃亡中度过余生
who'll be on the lam the rest of our lives,
时刻担心被捕吗
always feeling the hot breath of Johnny Law on our necks?
错 这意味着我们是一只精英小队 精英中的精英
No! It means, as elite units go, we're the elitest of the elite.
我们第二 就无人敢称第一
Top shelf in the bureau. The penultimate, plus one.
菜鸟哪去了
Where'd Private go?
哦 在这 D-3
Oh, there he is. D-3.
-哦 菜鸟现在售价多少 -3.50美刀 老大
- Oh, Private. How much is he? - He's $3.50, sir.
即使卖的是菜鸟 这价格也太离谱了
Well, that's outrageous. Even for Private.
长官 机器自己动了
Sir, the machine is alive!
小售货机 我可不喜欢你这态度
I don't think I like your attitude, vending machine.
还有你定的价格 快放了它们
Or your prices! Release them!
这是
What the...?
威尼斯
-科斯基 分析战况 -所有证据都表明
- Kowalski, analysis. - All evidence indicates...
我芝士条吃多了
I ate too many Cheezy Dibbles.
我们在明敌人在暗 我又渴炸了
We're behind enemy lines and incredibly thirsty.
瑞哥 带我们越狱
Rico, bust us out of this delicious prison.
干得漂亮 瑞哥
Nice work, Rico.
你是队里得力的一员
You are a meaningful and valued member of this team.
菜鸟 快跟上 别说话
Private, quit lollygagging. And regular gagging.
好黑 还有不详的预感 我最不喜欢的两种感觉都有了
Dark and ominous... Two of my least favorite traits in a room.
-快看 这有一个按钮 -别碰 菜鸟
- Oh, look! A button. - Private, don't!
-我不是说了吗 -对不起 你刚说啥
- Now, what have I told you about... - Sorry, what?
这看起来像可以杀人的激光器
It looks like some sort of giant laser sent to kill us all, sir.
-这也有一个 -别按
- Another one. - No!
-什么 -小淘气们
- Wha...? - Naughty, naughty.
美丽的鸟儿就应该呆在笼子里
Pretty birds belong in their cages.
太伤人心了 人家很高兴见到你们呢
Now, that's just hurtful. And I was so happy to see you again.
老大 科斯基 瑞哥
Skipper, Kowalski, Rico...
还有这个可爱的小菜鸟
and sweet little Private. Boop!
你是谁
Who are you?
人们都叫我布赖恩博士
The humans know me as Dr. Octavius Brine.
知名基因学家 芝士爱好者
Renowned geneticist, cheese enthusiast,
中央台慈善计划的长期志愿者
and frequent donor to NPR pledge drives.
但是你们认识的是曾经的我
But you know me by a different, much older name.
你们可能永远也不想听到那个名字
A name perhaps you'd hoped you'd never hear again.
像幽灵一样 生活的阴影
A phantom! A shadow of a former life!
我 就 是
I... am...
戴夫
Dave!
-科沃斯基 -抱歉 长官 没印象
- Kowalski? - Sorry, sir, no clue.
戴夫
Dave!
-戴夫 -戴夫
- Dave! - Dave!
- Dave? - Dave!
-戴夫 -戴夫
- Dave. - Dave!
抱歉
Sorry.
等等 我住在那边
Wait. Wait. I... I live this way.
-戴 继续 -你们真的记不得我了吗
- Go ahead, Dan, continue. - You seriously don't remember me?
戴夫 戴夫 噢 是你啊 好长时间没见了
Dave! Dave! Right! Oh, yeah, long time.
你妻子还好么
How's the wife?
我根本没结婚
I've never been married.
你们可能不记得我了 但我永远也忘不了你们
You may not remember me, but I could never forget you.
我们一起来追忆一下
Let's shake up some old memories.
那是在纽约
New York City.
中央公园动物园
The Central Park Zoo.
生活原本很美好
Life was good.
宽敞的环境 给力的展厅
Roomy tank, great location,
绝佳的视野
monkey-house views.
当然还有
And, of course...
我的一群狂热粉
my adoring legion of fans.
-酷 -戴夫
- Cool. - Dave!
一个会变魔术的章鱼
The octopus of a thousand tricks.
-好厉害 -我当时受到万千宠爱
- Awesome! - I was the total package.
-哇 -孩子们
- Wow. - Hey, kids!
你们一定要看看这个 快来
You got to see this. Get up here quick!
-快来 孩子们 快点 -然后你们来了
- Come on, kids. Come on... - And then you arrived.
它们好可爱
Oh, they're so adorable!
同志们 微笑 招手
Just smile and wave, boys. Smile and wave.
-你们抢走了我应有的一切 -它们太可爱了
- And took everything from me. - They're so cute!
-太可爱了 -你见过更可爱的么
- They're so adorable. - Have you ever seen anything cuter?
四只可爱的企鹅宝宝
Four adorable baby penguins.
从那以后 没人喜欢我这只老章鱼了
With you around, no one wanted an old octopus anymore.
戴夫 该走了
"Out you go, Dave."
然后我就被踢来踢去
And so it went, over and over,
-先是动物园 然后被扔到水族馆 -爸爸 快看
- at zoo after aquarium. - Dad, look!
喂 挡到我看企鹅了
I can't see the penguins, man!
你们包揽了所有的表演秀
Adorable penguins stole the show.
我的人生却不再辉煌
While I was shunned.
被人遗忘
Forgotten.
不被人喜欢
Unwanted.
孤独
Alone.
听起来好糟糕
That sounds awful.
确实
Oh, it was.
然后我意识到 有些人不废吹灰之力就受人喜爱
I came to realize some creatures are born to get all the love.
我们这些人什么都得不到
The rest of us get nothing!
这么多年支撑我的唯一信念就是
The only thing that has kept me going all these years is my
一定要报仇
burning thirst for revenge!
还有我全球的雪景水晶球
And my precious souvenir snow globe collection.
你有毛病吗
What is wrong with you?!
噢 戴瑞啊戴瑞
Oh, Daryl, Daryl, Daryl,
你不能把你的遭遇都怪罪我们
you can't blame us for what happened to you.
当然可以 这就是复仇
Can. That's how this whole revenge thing works.
用这个 我就可以彻底摧毁你们
And with this, I finally have the power to destroy you.
哎呀
Crikey!
此处Nicolas Cage与著名影星尼古拉斯凯奇谐音
尼古拉斯 抓住它们
Nicolas, cage them.
丹尼斯 我有不好的消息告诉你们
I've got some bad news for you, Dennis.
你惹错鸟了 因为我们是打不败的
You messed with the wrong birds. Because we are an elite unit,
精英中的精英 会让你不堪一击
the best of the best. Cream of the corn on a platinum cob.
我们会抓住你的致命绿色炸弹
And we're gonna take your deadly
然后离开这里
green goop and sashay right out the exit hatch.
那就让我瞧瞧你们的厉害吧
And just how are you going to do that?
装配秘密武器
Deploy secret weapon.
-芝士 辣死我了 -快走
- The cheese, it burns! - Roll out.
给我追
After them!
同志们 像在古巴那次一样
All right, boys, it's just like Cuba.
出租
Taxi!
来点音乐 欢快点的
How about some music? Something chase-y.
它们追来了
Here they come.
-快走 -快划 快划
- Let's move. - Stroke! Stroke! Stroke again!
再划快一点
Stroke some more! Stroke!
快划 快划 抱歉 快划
Stroke! Stroke! Stroke! Sorry! Stroke! Stroke!
星空字幕组
SSK•FanSub
－六点钟方向有情况 -科斯基 报告战况
- We got baddies, six o'clock. - Kowalski, battle formation.
关注新浪微博
@SSK字幕组
你们这群笨蛋要打架么 出手吧
So you squeegees want to do the gondola mambo? Let's dance.
我的妈 我看不见路了
Mother-of-pearl, that stings! I've lost visual.
-科沃斯基 带路 -左边
- Kowalski, be my eyes. - Left.
右边 右边 往上
Right, right! Up!
低头
Duck.
-解决了 -击中 长官
- I think I got 'em. - They are down, sir.
干得漂亮
Excelente.
-老大 -他们追上来了
- Skipper! - They're back up.
我们无路可逃了
And we are running out of canal.
老天爷啊 全力备战
Parker Posey! Go all-terrain.
你会嫁给我么
Will you marry me?
一号引擎失效
We've lost engine one!
-二号也是 还有三号 -四号
- And two and three. - Four!
-启用紧急备用装置 -是的 老大
- Switch to emergency power. - Aye, aye, Skipper.
前面是一车西瓜 没路了
We've got melons! Dead ahead!
我能看见了 瑞哥 绿色炸弹
I can see. Rico, the glowy thing!
又看不见了
Venetian blinded again!
-我们被围堵了 -启动自毁程序
- We've been boarded. - Initiate self-destruct sequence.
-漂亮 -喔
- Nice. - Whee!
说真的 没想到我们还真有自毁程序
Frankly, I'm surprised we had a self-destruct sequence.
同志们 作战准备
All right, boys, battle stance.
我们正在准备着呢 长官
We're in battle stance, sir.
很好 准备突破重围
Okay, good. Now we spring our trap.
还不确定被困的是谁呢
I'm not sure they're the ones that are trapped, sir.
科沃斯基 还记得我们
Kowalski, remember our
讲过的没啥帮助的计划么
little talk about true but unhelpful comments?
-是的 长官 -有的时候还是要随机应变
- Yes, sir. - Sometimes we just have to wing it.
哇
Wow.
抱歉 老大 是我低估了你的作战计划
Sorry for underestimating the plan, Skipper.
科沃斯基 我理解 以后不要再质疑我了
It's okay, Kowalski. Just don't ever doubt me again.
这到底是怎么回事
Now, what the heck is going on?!
企鹅们 淡定
Remain calm, penguins.
你们现在受北风特工局的保护
You are now under the protection of the North Wind.
救你们就不用谢了
You're welcome.
我的天啊
My gosh.
你们这群家伙太可爱了 太太太可爱了
You guys are so cute. You guys are just so, so cute!
毛茸茸
And cuddly.
嘿 走开 别抱了
Hey, get away! No more hugs!
好像被毛茸茸的小狗舔一样
It's like being licked by a basket full of puppy dogs.
大力熊 大力熊
Corporal! Corporal!
导航路线回北风特工局总部
Chart a course back to North Wind headquarters.
伊娃 通知他们我们带证人过去
Eva, inform them that we're bringing in witnesses.
菜鸟 芝士条给我
Private, Dibble me.
我们不会跟你走的
We're not going anywhere with you.
我们都不知道你们是谁
We don't even know who the heck you are.
北风特工局是一群精英组成的
The North Wind is an elite undercover interspe...
北风特工局是一群精英
The North Wind is an elite under...
一群精英
An elite undercover interspecies...
负责帮助
...task... force, dedicated to help...
帮助
helping...
负责帮助
Dedicated to helping...
帮助那些遭受困难的弱势动物
Dedi... Dedicated to helping animals who can't help themselves.
-像企鹅 -是么 那你是谁
- Like penguins. - Really? And you are?
-我的名字是机密 -机密 这是什么 荷兰话么
- My name is classified. - Classified? What is that, Dutch?
-真心听不懂你的口音 -你说什么
- Can't really hear the accent. - Excuse me?
-这口音听懂了 -我的名字不叫机密
- There's the accent. - No, my name isn't Classified.
我的名字是机密的
My name is classified
因为我是这个突击队的头头
because I am the leader of this strike team.
这是海豹 叫爆豹 擅长武器和爆破
The seal is Short Fuse, weapons and explosives.
这是大力熊 他是我们的大力士
The bear is Corporal, he's our muscle.
这是猫头鹰伊娃 负责情报和分析
And the owl is Eva, intelligence and analysis.
好吧 机密探员 我们恰好也是一支精英队伍呢
Well, Agent Classified, we happen to be an elite unit, too.
自毁程序已启动
Self-destruct sequence activated.
-你们真应该给这些按钮
- You know, you should really
贴上标签的 -倒计时三 二 一
label these things. - In three, two, one...
我叫老大 是我们队的头儿 后面那位是科沃斯基
The name's Skipper. I run this outfit. Back there is Kowalski.
他是我们的行动参谋 说点机智的话 科沃斯基
He's the brains of our operation. Say something smart, Kowalski.
看见没 他完全和我们不一个境界
See? He's working on a whole 'nother level.
还有瑞哥 他是我们的爆破专家
And Rico, he's our demolition expert.
他毁掉那沙发
He destroyed that chair
完全为了开心 就是这么任性
for the sheer fun of it. No reason at all.
这位是菜鸟
And then there's Private.
他算是 我们队的秘书兼吉祥物
He's... he's sort of our, you know, secretary/mascot.
-好萌 -好可爱 哦 不好意思
- Cute. - And cuddly. Oh, sorry.
我们来看看这又可爱又萌的手挡有什么本事
Well, let's see how well "Cute and cuddly" Handles this next bit.
这狗狗门不错嘛
Nice doggy door.
喔
Wow.
瞧瞧这个
Look at this.
喔 喔 喔 这地儿不错嘛 机密先生
Well, well, well. Not a bad place you got here, Classified.
多谢夸奖 我不叫机密
Thank you. That's not my name.
到达十七停机坪
Arrival at pad 17.
北大西洋
南大西洋
印度洋
好了 小企鹅们
All right, tiny penguins,
在北风特工局
the best way for the North
保护像你们这种可怜动物的最佳方案是
Wind to protect helpless animals like yourselves
将布莱恩博士绳之以法 因为你们去过他的潜艇
is to bring Dr. Brine to justice. Now, you were inside his sub,
所以 你们要把知道的一切都告诉我
so I need to know everything you know.
-嘿 -赶紧把你们知道的全告诉我
- Hey! - Just tell me everything you know.
好吧 第一条
All right. Numero uno:
-千万别在郁金香之争中相信荷兰人 -郁金香之争
- Never trust a Dutchman in a tulip fight. - Tulip fight...
加拿大正在秘密训练一支大脚野人军队
Canada is secretly training an army of Sasquatch.
而热狗 其实只有百分之十七是狗肉做的
Hot dogs are, in fact, only 17 percent actual dog.
不是让你说每一件事
Not "Everything" Everything. Just...
只需要告诉我关于奥克塔维厄斯·布莱恩绑架你们的所有细节
everything regarding your abduction by Dr. Octavius Brine.
-你怎么不早说呢 -什么
- Why didn't you say so? - What?
我们小队发现奥克塔维厄斯·布莱恩博士
My team has uncovered that Dr.
真实的名字其实是德里克
Octavius Brine is actually an individual known as Derek.
-戴夫 -是戴夫 章鱼戴夫
- Dave. - As Dave the octopus.
是章鱼么 不 布莱恩博士不是章鱼 他是
An octopus? No. Dr. Brine is not an octopus. He is...
一条章鱼 正是如此 我们的情报也是这样的
An octopus. Precisely. That's exactly what our intel indicated.
把羊放走
Release the sheep.
海陆战队研究所
不过你们肯定不知道的是
What you, of course, could not know is that Dr.
布莱恩博士在威尼斯的实验室
Brine's laboratory in Venice
正在密研制一种
is secretly developing a
毁灭性武器 叫做美杜莎血清
doomsday weapon called the "Medusa Serum."
美杜莎血清
-但是你不知道的是 德里克 -是戴夫
- But what you don't know is that Dirk... - Dave.
-戴夫不会用他的巴祖卡血清 -是美杜莎血清
- Dave won't be using his bazooka serum... - Medusa Serum.
他的美杜莎血清吓唬人了
Medusa Serum on anybody.
-这回说对了 -给他们看看 瑞哥
- That part is accurate. - Show him, Rico.
你偷了美杜莎血清
You stole the Medusa Serum?
偷了美杜莎血清 拯救了世界
Well, stole the serum, saved the day,
替你完成了任务 随你怎么说
did your job for you. Call it what you will.
-德比 -是戴夫
- Debbie! - Dave.
-戴夫 -他黑进了我们系统
- Dave! - He hacked into our system.
怎么没声音啊
Where's the sound?
戴夫 你的麦克风没打开
Dave. Your microphone, it's not on.
我什么都听不见
I can't... I can't hear anything.
按一下麦克风图案的按钮
Click on the button with the picture of the microphone.
-每次有坏人打进来的时候就会这样 -你好 有人吗
- Every time a villain calls in, this happens. - Hello? Hello?
现在能听到了 但是又看不到了
Now we can hear you, but we cannot see you.
太烦人啦 每次都这样
So annoying. Every time.
-就像和我父母视频的时候一样 -现在呢
- It's like talking to my parents. - How about now?
-吼吼 -棒呆了
- Hurray! - Great!
是啊 看到你了 太棒了
Yes, we've got you; that's fantastic.
-好极了 我们说到哪儿了
- Excellent. Now, where was I?
戴夫
Dave!
大家好 北风特工局 看来你们已经见过我的老朋友了
Greetings, North Wind. I see you've met my old zoo-mates.
谁跟你是朋友 我可不好你这口
We were never mates. There was no mating.
投降吧 戴夫 你已经黔驴技穷了 因为我已经偷了你那
Turn yourself in, David. You're powerless now that I've stolen
-宝贵的美杜莎血清 -什么 就你 那不是你偷得
- your precious Medusa Serum. - What? You? You didn't steal that.
-都结束了 -都结束了么
- It's over. - It's over?
那我为什么还给你打电话
Then why did I call you?
好奇怪 哦 可能是为了给你看这个
Weird. Oh, maybe it was to show you this.
四只企鹅可用不了这么多血清啊
That is a lot of serum for four penguins.
哦 你以为就只针对你们四个么
Oh, you thought this was just about you four?
不 不不不
No, no, no, no, no, no.
我们才刚刚开始
We're just getting started.
现在 恕我失陪 我要去购物
Now, if you'll excuse me, I have to go do some shopping...
买点复仇用品
for revenge!
等等 怎么关这个
Wait, how do you...
按哪个键 是红色的还是
What do I push? Is it the red or...
我以为是这个 不是这个
I thought it was the... It's not this...
-有紧急情况 -转到大屏幕
- Incoming alert. - Put it on the screen.
警告
柏林动物园有十五只企鹅失踪
The Berlin Zoo... 15 penguins missing.
柏林
-戴夫正在绑架其他企鹅 -辣么可爱辣么萌
- Dave's kidnapping other penguins! - No doubt cute and cuddly.
-我们必须行动 什么 -我们必须行动 什么
- We have to move! What? - We have to move! What?
-该我们上场了 -伙计们 快集合
- Time for our A-game. - Everybody, huddle up.
大力熊 准备好飞机 我去启动北风泽塔程序
Corporal, ready the jet. I'm initiating North Wind Protocol Zeta.
伦敦公园又有十二只企鹅失踪
12 more penguins taken from London Zoo.
好了 伙计们 机会来了
Okay, boys, this is it. The
我们这辈子翘首以盼的任务
mission we've been preparing for our entire lives.
我们不拿下戴夫 誓不罢休
We're gonna take down Dave or die trying.
-科沃斯基 取消我们的表演课 -是的 长官
- Kowalski, cancel our improv class! - Yes, sir.
-瑞哥 上装备 -好
- Rico, equipify. - Hi!
菜鸟 给爷笑一个
Private, do that little thing I like.
-还是很搞笑 -老大 有好消息
- It's still funny. - Skipper, good news.
-这次表演课取消不扣分 -长官 飞机准备好了
- I got them to credit our class. - Sir, the jet is ready.
好样的 宝贝儿们 就像十九届超级碗一样
Oh, yeah, baby! Just like Super Bowl 19!
他们在偷我的东西
They're stealing my stuff!
不 这次任务不能交给
No! This mission has no place
一群摇头晃脑的废物企鹅们
for a pathetic waddle of useless penguins!
-说谁废物呢 -够了
- Who are you calling pathetic? - Enough!
看见没 瑞哥 所以说好东西不能留给你
See, Rico, that's why you can't have nice things.
知道吗 其实我也很懂电脑的
You know, I'm pretty good with computers myself.
穿上你们的睡衣吧 小企鹅们
Put on your jammies, penguin.
-他们睡着了更萌 -我可不这么想哦
- They are even cute when they're asleep. - Not to me.
我要这些小鸭子离我远一点 别搀和我的任务
I want these butterballs out of my way and out of my mission.
把他们运到安全屋
Ship them to one of our safe houses.
那个世界上最偏僻的地方
The most remote place on the planet.
国际快递
目的地
马达加斯加
-我们到底在哪儿 -空气含氧量好低
- Where the heck are we? - Oxygen content is low.
我建议大家减少呼吸
I suggest we limit our breathing.
菜鸟
Private!
抱歉啦 我一飞起来就胀气
Sorry! I get gassy when I fly.
-就是这样 没错 -我们肯定是在飞机上
- Toot sweet! He does. - We must be on a plane.
北风特工局对我们做了什么
What did North Wind do to us?
他们给了我们徽章
They gave us badges.
不是徽章 是镇定飞镖
Not badges, tranquilizer darts.
该死的机密
Classified!
那下流卑鄙的狗玩意想把我们踢出任务
That low-down dirty dog is trying kick us off the mission.
他觉得我们不能拯救企鹅
He thinks we can't save
就因为我们也是企鹅
the penguins because we're just "Penguins."
企鹅与我们血肉相连 他们是我们同类
Well, penguins are our flesh and feathers. They're us.
能拯救我们的只有我们自己
And if anyone's gonna save us, it's us.
但是老大 我们正在五英里的高度
But, Skipper, we've got to be five miles up.
-这样我们的选择就很少了 -我的选择我做主
- That pretty much limits our options. - I make my own options.
帅呆了 老大 但是我们现在冲出飞机了肿么办
Brilliant move, Skipper, but now we seem to be outside the plane.
我刚才也是脑袋一热
Well, kind of got caught up in the moment.
看来我真有后见之明
Well, hindsight's 20/20.
好了 科沃斯基 该你来善后了
Okay, Kowalski, your turn to pick up the slack.
哦 要不搭那架飞机吧
Oh, why don't we catch that plane?
鸟群撞击 记录下来
Bird strike, log it.
还有一个目标 在十二点方向
We've got another target at 12 o'clock.
好 也就十一点半 跟着我飞 宝贝儿们 我们要火速前进
Good, it's only 11:30. Follow me, boys! We're going in hot.
-别炫耀了 菜鸟 -对准头等舱
- No one likes a show-off, Private. - Aim for first class!
我没事
I'm okay!
科沃斯基 这飞机是往哪儿开的
Kowalski, where does this aircraft go?
看这面包圈的奇怪形状 我觉得是飞往巴黎
From the odd shape of this bagel, I'd say we're headed for Paris.
法国 算了吧 那里的税收太高了
France? Forget it! Not with their tax laws!
-那我建议空中转机 -我准了
- Then I would suggest a mid-air transfer. - Affirmative.
花生 花生 花生
Peanuts! Peanuts! Peanuts, peanut,
peanut, peanut, peanut, peanut, peanut!
-没有花生了 老大 -那就椒盐脆饼干 菜鸟
- We're out of peanuts, Skipper! - Try pretzels, Private.
有了
Bingo.
香港
我们的飞机来了 兄弟们
There's our ride, boys.
我得走了 美女 危险就是我的情人
Can't stay, doll. Danger is my mistress.
瑞哥 再飞高点儿
Rico, more height.
椒盐脆饼 脆饼 脆饼
Pretzels! Pretzels! Pretzel,
脆饼 脆饼 脆饼也没了
pretzel, pretzels! We're out of pretzels!
是么 我们走得正是时候
Yeah? Then we're leaving just time,
这些人都开始慌了
'cause these folks are gonna freak!
展开机翼
Deploy flaps.
瞄准目标
Stay on target!
会赶上的 我们会赶上的
We're gonna catch it, we're gonna catch it!
哎呀 我们赶不上了
Crikey! We're not gonna catch it!
等下 老大在哪儿
Wait a minute, where's Skipper?
是时候开开脑洞了 快抓住那些箱子 伙伴们
Time to get creative. Start grabbing boxes, boys.
去吧
Going long!
哦 菜鸟 别摆弄那些背包了
Oh, Private, stop playing
找点有用的
with those backpacks. Find something useful.
这才对嘛 我们开动吧
Now we're talking. Let's get to work.
四百米
400 meters.
-三百米 -说美国话 科沃斯基
- 300 meters! - Speak American, Kowalski!
抱歉 先生 218码 109码
Sorry, sir. 218 yards. 109 yards.
好了 下一步要做什么很明确了
Okay, then. It's clear what we need to do next.
一小时之后
这个feel倍儿爽
That feels right.
跳的漂亮 伙伴们 回到文明社会来
Impressive bouncing, boys. Now, then, back to civilization.
要想打败德克斯特
If we're gonna take Dexter down,
我们必须知道下一个目标在哪
we need to know where he's gonna strike next.
里约热内卢
耶
Yeah!
进啦
Goal!
以利亚 请把他们带走
Elijah, would you please take them away.
企鹅脚印 还是新鲜的 我们刚好跟戴夫错过了
Penguin footprints, still warm. We just missed Dave.
-见鬼 让他跑了 -那么多企鹅啊
- Blast it, he's gone. - So many penguins!
-老大 他又开始暴躁饮食啦 -大力熊
- Boss! He's stress-eating again! - Corporal?
-好了 好了 -揉揉肚子不要生气啦
- There, there. - Rub the angry out of the tummy.
大力熊 集中注意
Corporal? Fo... focus.
我们去拯救那些无助的企鹅 因为
We are going to save those helpless penguins, because...
因为我们是北风特工 而没人
we are the North Wind, and no one...
没人能够阻挡我们
no one breaks the Wind.
没人能阻挡我们
No one breaks the Wind.
这才是好熊熊
There's a good Corporal. Now,
我们已经拯救了那四只企鹅 不是么
we rescued those four penguins already, didn't we?
将他们舒适温暖的运到了
Shipped them off all cozy and
马达加斯加 为什么会有哔哔响的声音
snug to a Madagascar... How come there's beeping?
先生 那些企鹅 就没到达马达加斯加
Sir, those penguins... They never made it to Madagascar.
什么 他们现在在哪儿
What? Well, where the dickens are they?
科沃斯基 报告我们的坐标
Kowalski, what are our coordinates?
根据我的计算
From my calculations,
我们到达了爱尔兰 都柏林的中心
we've arrived in the center of Dublin, Ireland.
上海
好了 勇士们 我们要入乡随俗 大河之舞
All right, soldiers, we got to blend in. Riverdance.
没时间去亲吻巧言石了 亲们
No time to kiss the Blarney stone, boys.
我们需要找到戴夫的具体位置 要快
We need to find intel on Dave's location, pronto.
好嘞 你 告诉我戴夫在哪儿 快说
All right, you, where's Dave! Give us the goods. Spit it out!
别逼我用武力
Don't make me use shillelagh!
长官 那只是个鱿鱼宝宝
Sir, that's... That's a baby squid.
抱歉 孩子
Sorry, laddie.
沦落到这爱尔兰岛上 一点儿头绪也没有
Stranded on the Emerald Isle without a single clue.
-我跟爱尔兰没缘分啊 -老大 快看
- Well, so much for the luck o' the Irish. - Skipper, look!
天呐 有人会说盖尔语吗
Begorrah! Does anyone speak Gaelic?
没有 不过看起来戴夫没闲着
No. But it looks like Dave's been busy.
他已经在瓜达哈拉哈偷走了企鹅
He's stolen penguins from Guadalajara!
-马德里 -巴黎
- Madrid! - Paris!
-雅典 -班加罗尔
- Athens! - Bangalore!
-杜塞尔多夫 -大阪
- Dusseldorf! - Osaka!
-里约热内卢 -内罗比
- Rio de Janeiro! - Nairobi!
-阿姆斯特丹 -巴吞鲁日
- Amsterdam! - Baton Rouge!
戴夫收藏的雪花水晶球系列
Dave's snow globe collection.
他去了把他踢出来的每家动物园和水族馆
It's every zoo and aquarium he got kicked out of!
别告诉我他去了哪儿
Don't tell me where he has been,
告诉我他下一站去哪儿
tell me where he will have has been next.
等等 这是什么 瑞哥 这是本书 是电影 是舞台剧
Wait, what is it, Rico? It's a book! It's a film! It's a play!
第一个词 两个音节 听起来是
First word. Two syllables. Sounds like...
听起来像上
Sounds like "Huuh"? Sounds like "Hyech!"
什么城市以上字开始
What starts with "Hyech"?
上海
Shanghai.
戴夫还没去过那儿
Dave hasn't been there yet,
老大 如果我们快点儿 可以阻止他
Skipper. If we hurry, we can still stop him.
干得漂亮 瑞哥
Nice work, Rico.
收拾好家伙 兄弟们 是时候去打击犯罪了
Pack your bagpipes, boys. It's time to blow this potato stand.
就是这儿了 上海著名的都柏林区
So this is it. Shanghai's famous Little Dublin district.
-老大 看啊 -看见你了 菜鸟
- Skipper, look! - I see you, Private.
这位踮着脚的那男孩儿是谁呀
Who's the big boy standing on his tippy-toes?
-什么 不是 我是说 -我只想一口把你吃掉
- Wha...? No, I mean... - I just want to eat you up.
老大 看 在菜鸟上面 戴夫的下一个目标
Skipper, look! Above Private! Dave's next target...
上海著名的企鹅美人鱼
Shanghai's famous mermaid penguins.
好眼力 科沃斯基 你再次
Good eye, Kowalski. And once again,
证明了自己是
you've proved that you are
我们队伍里有价值的成员
a meaningful and valued member of this team.
女士们先生们 上海海底世界很荣幸向大家介绍
Ladies and gentlemen, Shanghai Marine World is pleased to present
世界闻名的美人鱼企鹅
our world-famous Mermaid Penguins!
今晚 美人鱼们将为全世界失踪的企鹅
Tonight, our mermaids dedicate their performance
倾情奉上表演
to all the missing penguins around the world.
愿你们安全 小伙伴们 无论你们在哪里
Stay safe, little guys, wherever you are.
我们祝愿你们早点回家
And we hope you come home real soon.
都把眼睛瞪大了 兄弟们 戴夫可是伪装大师
Keep those eyes roving, boys. Dave is a master of disguise.
他可能会是一个小孩 一株植物 甚至是你或者我
He could be a small child, a house plant, maybe even you or me!
-是你吗 科沃斯基 -嘿 等一等
- Is it you, Kowalski? - Hey, hold on.
等一下
Wait a minute.
找到了 装得真像啊 戴夫 咔嚓 哗啦 呱啦行动开始
Bingo! Nice try, Dave! Operation Flash, Splash and Crash is a go!
-棒极了 -各就各位
- Splendid! - Take positions.
企鹅喂食时间两分钟后开始
Penguin feeding time will begin in two minutes.
目标正在三十码处靠近
Target, 30 yards and closing.
就位了 老大
In position, Skipper.
-瑞哥 汇报情况 -已就位
- Rico, report. - In position.
-菜鸟 听着 -是的 老大
- For you, Private. - Yes, Skipper!
-这是你的美人鱼套装 -什么
- Here's your mermaid costume. - What?
我们需要分散注意 而且 坦白说
We need a diversion. And, frankly,
这身你穿上最好看
you're the only one who can pull off that look.
但是我想做更有用的事 我想帮助我们团队 老大
But I can do more, Skipper. I want to help the team.
真正的帮助团队 如果你觉得我准备好了 其实我已经准备好了
Really help the team. If you think I'm ready, which I am.
如果你同意的话 甚至可能 你不同意
Assuming you agree. And perhaps even... if you don't?
我欣赏你的勇气 士兵
I like the moxie, soldier,
但是现在 我需要你穿上那套衣服
but right now, I need a tail on that tush
摆出你最美的笑容 你信我吗 士兵
and the cutest smile you've got. You trust me, soldier?
是的 老大
Aye, aye, Skipper.
嘿 喂食时间到了
Hey, it's feeding time!
星空字幕组
SSK•FanSub
目标离危险地区十玛远
Target, ten yards from flashpoint.
菜鸟 该你上了
Private, you're up.
关注新浪微博
@SSK字幕组
你简直美爆了
You just mermaid my day.
开始咔嚓环节
Flash is a go!
快看 他们把一只美人鱼放出来了
Look, they let one of the mermaids out of the tank!
-她好可爱啊 -没见过比她更可爱的了
- Oh, she's so cute. - It's the cutest thing I've ever seen.
戴上眼镜
Shields up!
目标已被闪晕 瑞哥 开始哗啦部分
Target is stunned. Rico, bring the Splash.
好的
Yeah!
哦 你在这干什么呢
Oh, what are you doing out here,
小可爱 快来 回到水槽里
cutie? Come on. Back in your tank.
保护好美人鱼 快点发现
Secure the mermaids and find me...
章鱼大卫
David the octopus.
有点晚喽 北风特工
A little late, North Wind.
任务完成 击个掌
Mission accomplished. High one!
大力熊 把那个
Corporal, take our prisoner...
属于我们的犯人 收押入监
the one that belongs to us... into custody.
-什么 -竟然把他化掉了 你们鸟鸟真变态
- What? - You melted him?! You birds are sick!
他从管道里逃跑了
He's going in through the pipes!
老大
Skipper!
菜鸟 菜鸟 你快离开那里
Private? Private! You got to get out of there!
-不不不 不不不 菜鸟 -老大
- No, no, no. No, no, no, no. Private! - Skipper!
菜鸟
Private!
-救命 -不要
- Help! - No!
好的 快走
Okay. Here we go.
快 快 快
Move, move, move!
他抓走了菜鸟 他逃走了 他逃走了
He's got Private! He's getting away. He's getting away!
-老大 北风特工局的飞机 -天助我也啊
- Skipper, the North Wind's plane. - Sweet chariot of the gods!
-但是你会开吗 伙计 -不试怎么知道
- But can you fly it, man? - There's only one way to find out.
使用手册
不 我还是看不懂
No, I... still can't read.
我们只好跟着感觉走喽
Then we're going off-book.
不 不 不不不
No! No, no, no, no!
过了 过了 过了 过了 过了
Too much, too much, too much, too much, too much!
-我已经找到窍门了 老大 -拉起来
- I'm getting the hang of this, Skipper. - Pull off!
好嘞 我们来救你了 菜鸟
Good! We're coming for you, Private!
这些荒唐的小胖子们又让大卫给跑了
Those ludicrous butterballs are letting David escape!
伊娃 保证道路通畅 短导引爆 大力熊 准备强行登机
Eva, secure transport. Short Fuse, Corporal, hitch us a ride.
开火
Fire!
接着
Go fetch.
保持平稳
Hold her steady.
长官 戴夫开得很快 我们的飞机太沉了
Sir, Dave is pulling ahead. We are too heavy.
哦 都怪我们的芝士条吃多了
Oh, curse our heavily cheese-dibbled diet!
瑞哥 给我来个西方赫尔辛基清仓大甩卖
Rico, give me a West Helsinki fire sale.
-好的 好的 -所有东西都扔掉
- Yeah, yeah. - Everything must go!
我了个
What the...
-全都扔了 长官 -你有没有冲马桶
- That's everything, sir. - Have you purged the chemical toilet?
-但是瑞哥在里面便便了15分钟 -让你冲就冲
- But Rico was in there for 15 minutes! - Just do it!
不 不不不不
No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
-自毁程序倒计时 五 -不要啊 菜鸟
- Self-destruct sequence in five, - No, Private!
-四 三 而 -挺住啊 士兵
- four, three, two... - Stay strong soldier!
一
...one.
老大日志
Skipper's log.
我们在海上漂浮了好几天的时候
Private has been kidnapped by Dave,
菜鸟已被戴夫绑架
while we have been cast adrift for what seems like days.
没有食物 没有淡水
No rations, fresh water...
也远远望不到陆地
or land in sight.
科沃斯基病得像条狗
Kowalski is sick as a dog.
而瑞哥 一直想要吃掉他
And Rico keeps trying to eat him.
拜托 请你住口吧
Just, please, just cut it out.
不知道我们还能坚持多久
Not sure how long we can hold on.
这可能是我最后一条记录
This may be my final entry.
2004年的波尔多右岸 有梨和白桃的香味
2004 Grand Cru. Hints of pear, white peaches.
-三文鱼味道太好了 -哦 我这辈子
- The salmon is delicious. - Oh, I have never been...
从来没喝过这么多
- ...more hydrated in my life.
-我来给你切块三文鱼
- Let me cut you a piece of the salmon.
-不用了 谢谢 我撑死了
- No, thank you. I'm stuffed.
-这是船上最美味的食物了
- It's the most delicious thing on the boat.
-我得松松我的多功能腰带了
- I have to loosen my utility belt.
-不用了 我饱了 把它扔到海里吧
- No, I'm full. Just dump it in the ocean.
要知道 我们可是同舟共济的啊
You know, we're all in the same boat here.
其实 我们不是
Actually, we're not. And
而且 你应该稍微关心一下
perhaps you could express a little more concern
你们偷窃并且毁掉一架价值一千九百万飞机的事实
over the fact that you stole and destroyed a $19 million vehicle!
账单寄给我
Bill me.
-大力熊 大力熊 -我们收到了一条信号 长官
- Corporal? Corporal? - We're picking up a signal, sir.
信号在西南方向五公里处
It's five klicks southwest,
停在了那个小岛上
but it stopped at that remote island.
陆地啊
Land?
干得不错啊 你找到陆地了
Good on you. You've tracked down some land.
不 你这个笨蛋
No, silly willy. We've
我们一直在跟踪你们的小秘书兼吉祥物
been tracking your little secretary/mascot.
什么 你们在菜鸟身上安了跟踪设备
What? You put a homing device on Private?
其实每个人都安了 当我用飞镖射你们的时候
All of you, actually, when I darted you.
你这下作
You low-down,
肮脏 污秽 龌龊
dirty, mangy, filthy,
长满跳蚤 满身骚臭的家伙
flea-bitten, bum-sniffing toilet drinker!
但是 干得好
But... good.
看见没 我早说过了
See, I told you.
应该让专业的来解决这些问题
You should've left this to the professionals.
892.
893 894
893. 894.
895.
你们好啊
Ahoy there!
企鹅们
Penguins.
我猜你们都想知道我为什么把你们抓来
I bet you're all just dying to know why I brought you here.
-他会杀了我们的 -什么 当然不会了
- He's gonna kill us all! - What? No.
我的美杜莎血清不会让人死掉的
My Medusa Serum doesn't kill anyone.
-那有什么好玩的 -那它会怎么样
- Where's the fun in that? - So, what does it do?
更加更加恐怖的事
Something much, much worse.
好吧 但是 具体是什么
Right. But, like, what specifically?
我就是带你们来见证这个的
Well, that's exactly what I came up here to show you.
我只需要一个实验对象
All I need is a test subject.
你好啊 小小虫
Hello, little buggy-boo!
是因为我叫的声音太吵了吗 我可以 哇
Is this about the chirping? 'Cause I could... Whoa!
哇
Whoa!
看好了 见证我释放美杜莎血清
Behold, as I unleash the full power
全部能量的时刻
of the Medusa Serum.
发射
Fire!
太棒了 成功了
Yes! It works!
我创造了一个怪物 我创造了一个怪物
I made a monster. I made a monster!
你们这些可爱的企鹅就是下一个
And all you adorable penguins are next!
哎呀
Crikey!
谁说的
Who said that?
不是
No.
不是 不是
No. No.
是你
Yes!
先生们 你们还记得菜鸟
Gentlemen, you remember Private.
哦 嘿
Oh, hey.
你早晚会遭报应的 戴夫
You'll never get away with this, Dave.
我的兄弟们就要来了
My brothers are coming,
我们齐心协力一定会
and together we'll take a
毁掉你这肮脏的计划
wrecking ball to your whole rotten operation.
停止猎鹅行动 各位
Call off the hunt, everyone.
看来精英小队会自己送上门来的
Turns out the elite unit will be coming to us.
哔
Boop.
伊娃
Eva?
你看到什么了
What do you see?
一共有三十个敌人
My count is 30 hostiles.
三十一个
31.
有两个站的很近
Those two are very close together.
我是说 身体上相互交叠
I mean, you know, intertwined,
但 并不是
physically, but... but not in...
集中精力 科沃斯基
Ixnay on the irtflay, Kowalski.
可怜的菜鸟 孤身一人
Poor Private. Alone,
身陷险境
helpless in the belly of that beast.
我们曾遇过很多高风险的困境 老大
We've faced some long odds before, Skipper,
但这是看起来是风险最高的 最诡异的一次
but these look like the longest and oddest.
我们若想成功 必须声东击西
If we're gonna pull this off, we'll need a diversion.
解除丛林伪装
Deactivating jungle camouflage.
-你能小点声么 -听着 机密特工
- Would you be quiet? - Listen, Classified...
短导引爆 你应该把他们拷在石头上
Short Fuse, you were supposed to handcuff them to the rock!
-少用全息图像蒙我 -我尝试了 但是他们没有手
- Don't you hologram me! - I tried, but they don't have hands.
他们只有脚蹼 老大
They just have flippers, boss.
我也有脚蹼 所以根本拷不住的
And I have flippers! So it's flipping useless!
好了 大狗狗 如果你不和我们合作
All right, pooch. If you won't work with us,
那最好为我们工作 我们的计划需要声东击西
you better work for us. Our plan requires a diversion.
我是这里的老大 尽管让我很头疼
I give the orders around here. Much as it pains me,
但是你必须为我们的行动声东击西 听懂了没
I need you to act as our diversion for our operation, understood?
不要 这是我们的计划 需要你去声东击西
Nope! This is our plan, and it requires you to cause a diversion.
-声东击西 -省东击西
- Die-version. - Dih-version.
-声 声 声 声 声 -省 省 省 省 省
- Die, die, die, die, die, die! - Dih, dih, dih, dih, dih, dih!
先生们 只有一个解决办法
Gentlemen, there is only one way to resolve this.
-我们应该接吻 -制定计划
- We should kiss. - Plan-off.
是的 制定计划 我就打算说这个的
Yep, plan-off. That's what I was gonna say.
制定计划吧
Plan-off.
这是戴夫的潜艇
Here's Dave's sub.
这个幼小 无助
And this young, helpless,
又脆弱的石头是菜鸟
vulnerable rock is Private.
这是戴夫
And here's Dave.
你们四个吹牛大王去分散那调章鱼的注意
While you four blowhards "Dih-vert" The octopi,
我们发动快速强烈的攻击
we strike fast and strike hard!
嘿耶 动起来 伙计们
Hi-yah! Get on in here, boys!
狠狠打他 瑞哥 使劲儿 科沃斯基 解救人质
Slap him silly, Rico! Come on! Kowalski, free the hostages!
就是要这个效果 大块头
Now, that's what I'm talking about, big fella!
解救菜鸟之后
With Private freshly liberated,
我们来个名至如归的击掌庆祝
we celebrate with a well-earned high one,
再把戴夫的残余部队一扫而光 有问题吗
and feast off Dave's sweet remains. Any questions?
哇哈 别闹
Whoa-hoa, hey, now!
哇 我是说 我真心佩服
Wow. I mean, truly impressive.
尤其是你抽打水果那一段
Especially the bit where you slap the fruit.
哦 大力熊 灯光暗点 短线引爆 眼镜拿来
Oh! Corporal, dim the lights. Short Fuse, glasses.
不好意思 我得快点说 这个计划很粗糙
My apologies. Had to rush a bit. The schematic's a little crude.
-这音乐是哪来的 -喔
- Where is that music coming from? - Wow.
好了 晚上九点五十分 老大 科沃斯基 和理查德 是吗
All right, at 21:50, Skipper, Kowalski and... Richard, was it?
把那些章鱼从岗位上引开
Die-vert the octopi away from their posts.
十点整 短线引爆用一组
At 22:00, Short Fuse breaches the hull
水下自导纳米电荷破坏船体
with a swarm of self-guided underwater nano-charges.
我叫它们 湿湿卡蹦
I call them "Wet kabooms."
-哦 不要这样 -好吧 抱歉
- Yes, please don't. - Okay, sorry.
-到了十点零二 敲敲门 -是谁啊
- At 22:02, knock, knock. - Who's there?
-北风特工 -北风特工谁呀
- The North Wind. - The North Wind who?
北风特工没时间解释
The North Wind who doesn't have
敲门笑话 因为我们忙着
time for knock-knock jokes because we're too busy
扳倒大卫呢
taking down Dave.
私人订制悬停油箱 检查完毕
Personal hover tank... check.
自动瞄准助飞器
Auto-targeting wing mounts.
这个必须有 到十点零九
Why not? At 22:09,
任务完成
mission accomplished.
看见没 我连头也不回
See that? I don't even look back.
轰的一声爆炸 我就潇洒离场
There's a huge explosion, and I just keep walking.
帅呆了 老大
Way to go, boss!
-这才是北风 怂货 -干得漂亮
- That's North Wind, sucker! - Nicely done.
说了那么多听不懂一个字
La-di, blah, blah, blah, blah.
好计划不仅仅是靠那些炫酷的玩意儿
A good plan is about more than effecty stuff and...
和丰富的辞藻
vocabulary words.
而你 你当然最会制定计划了
And you, you... you certainly know a good plan...
我是说 你们在上海的行动
I mean, your operation in
最终以眼睁睁看着戴夫带着你的伙伴逃跑告终
Shanghai allowed Dave to escape with... your boy.
我可没丢过一名组员 那感觉肯定 糟透了
I've never lost a member of my team. It must feel... awful.
那种愧疚啊 后悔啊
Can't imagine the guilt, the regret,
那种不可名状的感觉 难以想象
the feeling that, I don't know, that...
被抓的应该是你
it should have been you.
支持企鹅计划的人有
All for penguin plan?
支持北风特工计划的人有
All for North Wind plan?
他的计划更好
His... his is better.
什么
What?
抱歉 兄弟们 我这次不能带领你们了
I'm sorry, boys, but I can't lead you this time.
但是
But...
我们是一个团队
we're a team, and...
你是我们的老大 老大
and you're our skipper, Skipper.
我们不需要他们
We don't... we don't need these guys.
不 科沃斯基 但是菜鸟需要他们
No, Kowalski, but Private does.
我觉得 是时候交给专业人士来处理了
I think... it's time we leave it to the professionals.
-但是 长官 -就这么定了
- But, sir... - It's settled.
我们听从机密特工的命令
We take our orders from Agent Classified now.
这就是命令 瑞哥
That's an order, Rico!
好吧 机密特工
All right, Classified...
如何声东击西
what's the diversion?
这件丢人的事死都不能说出去
We take this shame to our graves.
双手同意
Agreed.
嘿
Hey!
-几点了 -十点整
- Time? - 22:00 hours.
收拾戴夫的时间到了
Time to take down Dave.
章鱼大卫 把你的触须举起来
David the octopus, show me your tentacles.
所有的触须
All of them.
我们甩掉他们了 老大
We lost them, Skipper.
别高兴得太早 这些短袜勒得我蛋疼
Not a moment too soon. These hosen are riding up my bundesliga.
好了 兄弟们 抓好你们的椰子 捂好耳朵
All right, boys, grab your coconuts and hold 'em tight.
机密特工马上就会扛着菜鸟
Classified should be walking away
伴着巨大的爆炸声归来
from a huge explosion with Private on his shoulder
三 二 一 来点欢迎仪式 瑞哥
in three... two... Give 'em a welcome home, Rico!
耶 就是这么炫酷 戴夫 菜鸟回来了
Yeah! In your face, Dave! The Private is back!
-欢迎回家 菜鸟 -耶 棒棒哒
- Welcome home, Private! - Yeah! All right!
就这样 好了
Here we go. All right.
长官 潜艇没有爆炸
Sir, the sub didn't explode, and...
而且我担心 放烟花是战术上错误
I fear the... fireworks may have been a tactical mistake.
淡定 别慌
Stay calm! Do not panic!
胜利是属于我们的 要充满爱 不要憎恨
We will still win! Be full of love! Don't hate!
追寻梦想 热爱自己 关爱他人
Follow your dreams! Love yourself! Love other people!
做真正的自己
Pick and choose your battles in life!
别让其他人告诉你该怎么做
Don't let anyone tell you what to do!
无视讨厌你的人 爱你身边的人
Ignore the haters! Love the one you're with!
-爱你身边的人 -伊娃
- Love the one you're with! - Eva.
我知道
I know.
欢迎 老大 科沃斯基 还有淘气鬼瑞哥
Welcome, Skipper, Kowalski and rootin'-tootin' Rico!
大伙儿全在这儿 真是太刺激了
The gang's all here! The mood is electric!
这是真的吗 终于齐全了
Is this really, finally everybody?
好吧 戴夫 你做了什么
All right, Dave, just what have you done with...
-菜鸟 -哦 兄弟们
- Private! - Oh! Guys!
-你现在怕了吧 戴夫 -真的吗
- You're in for it now, Dave! - Really?!
无论如何 来得太及时了 现在
Anyway, great catching up. Now,
谁准备好进行活企鹅实验了呢
who's ready to move on to live penguin testing?
你快把那杀伤性射线从菜鸟身上移开
You point that death ray away from Private right now!
这不是杀伤性射线 老大 他要把我们变成怪物
It's not a death ray, Skipper. He's gonna turn us into monsters!
没错 “接下来是什么呢 戴夫”
Yepper-doo! "And what comes next, Dave?"
入侵
Invasion!
可怕的变异企鹅
Horrible mutant penguins
被放到纽约的大街上
unleashed on the streets of New York City!
-你是魔鬼 -对 我是魔鬼
- You're the monster! - Yes! I'm the monster.
每一个人在我生命中的每一天都提醒我这一点
Everyone made that clear to me every day of my entire life.
但现在 让我们瞧瞧
But now, let's see how much
当你们变成怪物时人们有多爱你们
everyone loves you when you're the monster!
-老大 -你不能夺走菜鸟的可爱
- Skipper! - You can't take away Private's cuteness!
他是最可爱的 那是他天生的
He's the cute one! That's-that's his thing.
-什么 -那是小家伙的所有
- What? - It's all the little guy's got!
你超级可爱 我们最好启动
You are super cute. We better crank this up.
德鲁 拜瑞 调动力量
Drew, Barry, more power.
-准备好了吗 -谈判失败了
- Ready? - Negotiations have broken down.
瑞哥 回形针 把我们放出去
Rico, the paper clip! Bust us out of here!
我们需要那个回形针 赶快 战士们
We need that paper clip! Chop-chop, soldier!
不 回形针去哪儿了
No! Where's the paper clip?
菜鸟
Private!
不
No!
-菜鸟 -哦 不
- Private... - Oh, no.
我肢解了他
I disintegrated him.
不应该啊
That wasn't supposed to happen.
你这个疯子 你把他炸飞了
You maniac! You blew him up!
不
No.
哦 好吧 所以我们才要试验 人们
Oh, well, this is why we test things, people.
下一次我会降低点能量
I'll have to lower the power for the others.
全速向前 绅士们 把这些怪物送去曼哈顿
Full speed ahead, gentlemen. The monsters are due in Manhattan!
对不起
Sorry.
哎呀
Crikey.
没事 没事 章鱼
All right, all right, octopus.
无论戴夫给你多少钱 我会给你双倍
Whatever Dave's paying you, I'll double it.
-你是同意了吗 有人会说章鱼的语言吗 -对不起
- Is that a yes? Does anyone speak octopus? - Sorry.
-不会 完全不会 -他妈的
- No, not a clue. - Blast it.
你 放了 我们
You... free... us.
我们给你 许多鱼
We give you... many fishes.
那是什么
What is that?
-哦 太好了 -哦 不 我们就这样了
- Oh, great. - Oh, no! This is it!
我可不想黏糊糊得死
I don't want to die all squishy!
我们死定了死定了死定了死定了
We're dead! Dead! Dead! Dead!
哦 不 我们死定了
Oh, no, we're dead!
死定了死定了
Dead! Dead...!
我只是按了一个按钮
I pushed a button.
-太棒了 做得好 菜鸟 -做得好
- Super. Well done, Private! - Good work, malinki.
对 对 地
Yay. Yes. Yes.
按得超级棒 值得表扬称赞
Excellent button-pushing. Compliment, praise, et cetera.
好吧 特工 我们继续我们的任务
All right, agents, we are back in business.
等一下 老大 科斯基 瑞哥 还有所有的企鹅
Wait! Skipper, Kowalski, Rico, all those penguins,
-他们在那儿 -一大批章鱼军队也在那儿
- they're this way! - And so is a massive army of octopi.
只有我们回到
And as soon as we return to the
北风总部 拿到最新的设备
North Wind headquarters, grab fresh equipment,
设想一个粉碎性的新计划
and work up a smashing new plan,
我们会速速回来将戴夫拿下
we'll come speeding back and take down Dave.
但企鹅们现在身处险境 我们现在就得去
But the penguins are in danger! We have to go now!
别忘了 庞大的章鱼军队
Again, huge army of octopi.
所以 因为你失败过一次 你就要逃跑了
So, because you failed once, you're just running away?
我们没有失败 我们现在不是逃跑
We did not fail. And we are not running away.
我们只是在理智地重组
We're just very sensibly regrouping.
老大才不会在乎有没有好的计划先进的设备
Skipper wouldn't care. Plan or no, fancy equipment or no...
他不会丢下兄弟
he'd never leave a man behind.
那 我想我们不可能都成为企鹅 你说呢
Well, I suppose we can't all be penguins, can we?
不
No.
但或许你应该学学
But maybe you should be.
来吧
Come on.
好戏上演 同志们 纽约等着我们呢
Showtime, everyone! Big smiles for the Big Apple!
听着 桃瑞丝 你把我们变成怪物 那然后呢
Listen up, Doris! You turn us into freaks, and then what?
你认为那样做人们就会爱你
You think that's gonna make everybody love you?
不 但他们厌恶你们
No, but they'll despise you.
还有我确定那样我会很高兴的
And I'm sure gonna love that.
重大新闻 失踪的企鹅们已经被找到啦
Breaking news! The missing penguins have been found!
好了 根据我的记录
Okay. According to my notes,
基因研究者奥克塔维厄斯·布赖恩博士
genetic researcher Dr. Octavius Brine
已经找到了企鹅并
has found the penguins and is
把他们带到纽约的炮台公园
bringing them here to New York's Battery Park.
企鹅们回来了 哦 我的天哪 看
The penguins are coming back! Oh, my gosh! Look!
全世界的企鹅爱好者们 猜猜我找到了什么
Penguin lovers of the world, guess who I found.
企鹅 企鹅
Penguins! Penguins!
这并不简单 但看到企鹅们得到应得的待遇
It wasn't easy, but seeing the penguins get what they deserve
这一切都值得了
will make it all worthwhile.
这多么奇怪 我好激动啊
What a weird thing to say! I'm so excited!
快
Do it.
老大 老大 老大 瑞哥 科斯基
Skipper! Skipper! Skipper! Rico! Kowalski!
好像我还能听到他用微弱的声音呼喊我们
It's like I can still hear his little voice calling to us.
你们得离开这儿 快走
You have to get out of there! Move!
“你有一头老水牛 那儿
"You have a great otter, there.
-哞” -他会什么要说“哞”
- Moo." - Why would he moo?
你为什么问我 我又不是菜鸟的灵魂
What are you asking me for? I'm not Private's little ghost.
不
No!
你准备好了吗
Are you ready?!
太好了
Yeah!
Yay...!
你们的
Your new...
全新进化的
and improved...
企鹅们
penguins!
企鹅 企鹅
Penguins! Penguins!
什么
Wha...?
哦 人们爱你们 去给他们一个拥抱吧
Oh, the people love you. Just go give them a hug.
别让他们碰你
Don't let them touch you!
哦 不 发生什么了 没有人再喜欢你们了
Oh, no. What's happening? Nobody likes you anymore?
好吧 这乐趣和游戏才刚刚开始 看这 企鹅们
Well, the fun and games are just beginning. Watch this, penguins.
快叫 职业消灭害虫团队
Somebody call... the exterminators!
当职业消灭害虫团队把你们抓走 你们就永远回不来了
And when the exterminators take you away, you never come back.
哦 亲爱的
Oh, dear.
哦 不 哦 不 哦 不 我要做什么 我要做什么
Oh, no. Oh, no. Oh, no. What do I do? What do I do?
哎呀
Crikey!
那就过来吧 你们想过去吗 你们想挨揍吗
Come on, then. You want to go? You want some argy-bargy?
漏了一只
Missed one.
今天是公园最棒的一天了
What a wonderful day in the park.
老大
Skipper!
等等
Wait!
慢着 你在做什么
Hold on! What are you doing?!
老大
Skipper!
别吃那个
Don't eat that!
老大 听着 是我 菜鸟
Skipper, listen. It's me, Private.
我已经有计划了 但我需要你的帮助 我需要我的老大
I've got a plan, but I need your help. I need my Skipper.
-菜鸟 -对 是我
- Private? - Yes. That's it.
菜鸟 你还活着
Private, you're alive!
哦 天哪
Oh, God!
科沃斯基 你得冷静
Kowalski! You've got to get a grip!
科斯基 伊娃在担心你
Kowalski, Eva is worried about you.
真的吗 她说了什么 她有没有明确地提到我的名字
She is? What did she say? Did she say my name specifically?
我是说 有 有没有流泪
I mean, were there... were there tears?
细节 快 告诉我
Details, come on, tell me!
菜鸟 你还活着 过来
Private! You're alive. Come here.
这感觉有点儿奇怪 但我很开心
This feels a little awkward, but I'm happy.
瑞哥 你得听我们说
Rico! You need to listen to us.
我猜你也会有一样的反应
I guess you're kind of the same either way.
菜鸟
Private!
小心
Heads up!
我们又卷土重来了 兄弟们
Looks like we're back in business, boys.
我们的任务是拯救企鹅
And our business is saving penguin-kind.
-谁要加入我 -算我一个
- Who's with me? - Count me in.
-行动吧
- Let's do this! - Boo-hah!
-耶 让我们创造和感受力量吧
- Yeah! - Let's create and feel momentum.
长官 我们要这样站多久
Sir, how long do we stand here like this?
直到我们不能更酷炫为止
Until we've reached maximum coolness.
就是这样
There it is.
-现在我们需要的是一个计划 -我有一个
- Now all we need is a plan. - I've got one.
你偷了戴夫的射线
You stole Dave's ray?
那啥 我想如果我们能扭转射线
Well, I figured if we could reverse the ray,
我们能把所有企鹅都变回正常
we could turn everyone back to normal.
扭转射线
Reverse the ray?
这太机智了 但是 这不可能
That's brilliant! But... it's impossible!
为了扭转射线
In order to reverse the ray,
我们需要把美杜莎血清
we would need to replace the Medusa Serum
替换成另一种无敌可爱的能源
with a power source of almost immeasurable cuteness.
无敌可爱
Immeasurable cuteness?
我们究竟该怎么得到那种无敌可爱的能量
Where the heck are we supposed to get that?
不 等等 菜鸟 我们不知道那玩意对你有什么影响
No, wait. Private, no! We don't know what that will do to you!
-好吧 -射线 起作用了 起作用了
- All right! - The ray! It works! It works!
-菜鸟 你还好吗 -嗯
- Private! Are you okay? - Yes!
屁股 手 他的屁股上有一只手
Butt-hand! There's a hand attached to his butt.
那不是 之前不在那儿
That was not... that was not there before.
-离开那儿 这是命令 -允许为抗命令
- Get out of there! That's an order! - Permission to defy order.
-驳回允许 -我驳回你的驳回
- Permission denied! - Then I deny your denial.
这太冒险了 菜鸟 它都让你屁屁长手了
It's too risky, Private. It already made you sprout a butt-hand!
我知道这次非我不可了
I know it has to be me this time.
我想你也知道这一点
And I think you know it, too.
我是秘密武器
I'm the secret weapon.
我好高兴
I'm happy... and yet...
虽然我复仇了 我觉得
now that I have my revenge, I feel...
好空虚 就好像我一直需要的是
empty, as if what I needed all along was...
更多的报复 事实上 罗宾 写下来
more revenge! In fact... Robin, write this down...
明天我们去报复小猫 然后是小狗 小兔子 熊猫
Tomorrow we move on to kittens! Then puppies, bunnies, pandas...
查理兹 他们偷了发射器
Charlize, they're on the ray!
海伦 快去抓他们 威廉姆 制服他们
Helen, hunt them down! William, hurt them.
海里 活埋他们 休 杰克 坚守战斗岗位
Halle, bury them! Hugh, Jack, man the battle stations!
凯文 继续烤 我们还是需要那个胜利蛋糕
Kevin, bake on! We're still gonna need that victory cake!
这次我们一定要一击即中
We're only gonna get one shot at this,
兄弟们 我们要怎么处理那些雪花玻璃球
boys! How we doing on those snow globes?
分光镜准备完毕 随时待命
Beam splitter ready! Fire at will!
动手 老大
Do it, Skipper!
-没电了 -完了 老大
- Dead batteries?! - Game over, Skipper!
不
No!
瑞哥 去买电池 老大 科沃斯基
Rico, batteries! Skipper! Kowalski!
拖住那些章鱼 我们一定要成功
Hold off those octopi! We're doing this now!
你听到了 执行
You heard Private! Deploy!
滚回去 你们这些水里来的丑八怪
Get back, you aquatic savages!
在你后面 在你旁边 六点钟方向 十二点方向
Behind you! Beside you! Six o'clock! Twelve o'clock!
-他们正从四面八方过来
- They're coming from every direction!
-他们实在是太多了
- There's just too many of them!
-哇哦 -你们回来了
- Whoa. - You came back!
哦 难怪你要回头看爆炸呢
Oh... that's why you look back at the explosion.
我能想象
I can dream...
撤退型队列
Fallback positions!
离菜鸟远些
Stay away from Private!
跟我走吧 科沃斯基
Suck it up, Kowalski.
不
No!
结束了 老大
It's over, Skipper.
结束了 那可真奇怪 那为什么
Over? That's weird. Then why
瑞哥扔给我两节新的AA型电池呢
is Rico throwing me a fresh pair of double-A's?
-不 -遥控器
- No! - The remote!
瑞哥 芝士条
Rico! Dibble me!
成功了 菜鸟
It worked! Private!
抱歉 紧急情况 闪开 快闪开 快闪开
Excuse me. Emergency. Coming through. Make a hole! Make a hole!
别担心 你的周围
Don't worry, a chrysalis is
正形成一道茧 这非常正常
just forming around you. That's perfectly normal.
菜鸟
Private.
什么
Wha...?
菜鸟
Private?
-哦 看那儿 好气派 -你们好
- Oh! Look at that! Majestic. - Hello.
-菜鸟 -哦 嘿
- Private! - Oh! Hey!
-怎么了 你在 -我在看
- What's wrong? What are you... - Look out for the...
-我是不是 -当心眼睛
- Have I got something... - Cover your eyes.
-是不是 -别转头了
- Is there a... thing? - Don't turn your head.
那么 我看上去怎么样
So... how do I look?
你看上去滑稽极了
You're hideously disfigured
很可能会像球一样被追打玩弄
and will probably be hunted for sport.
-什么 什么
- What? - What?
我们从这场愉快的冒险中
If there's anything we've learned
学到的是 科沃斯基
from this delightful adventure... Kowalski...
外貌并不重要
It's that looks don't matter.
重要的是你做了什么
It's what you do that counts.
瞧瞧你所做的
And look at what you did.
是 长官
Yes, sir...
你是这个团队里最有意义最有价值的成员
you are the most meaningful and valued member of this team.
做得好 菜鸟
Way to go, Private!
好样的
Attaboy!
干的漂亮
Nicely done.
-好样的 菜鸟 你做到了 -我们以你为荣
- Way to go, Private! You did it! - We're so proud of you!
-你救了我们 -我们爱你 菜鸟
- You saved us! - We love you, Private!
-是啊 我们爱你 -你们这些企鹅
- Yeah, we love you! - You the penguin!
拉米雷茨
Ramirez!
-戴夫 戴夫
- Dave. - Dave!
什么 这不是真的吧
What? Are you kidding me?!
-戴夫 看看你 -你觉得这就完了
- Dave... look at you. - You think this is over?
-我才刚刚开始
- I'm just getting started.
我正打算 -我们该怎么处理他
I'm about to... - What do we do with him now?
现在打开
Open this right now!
给你 孩子
Here you go, kid.
酷
Cool!
祝你找到幸福 戴夫
I hope you find happiness, Dave.
下雪了 下雪了 下雪了
It's snowing! It's snowing! It's snowing!
It's snowing! It's snowing! It's snowing...
好的 现在 嗯
Right, now, then...
-我很难开口 -是想说“骨质疏松症”吗
- this is difficult for me to say. - Is it "Osteoporosis"?
你至少得口腔打开 骨质疏松症
You just got to lean into the vowel. Os-teo...
-不 不
- poro... - No! No.
我想说 你们四个是我见过最英勇的探员
I want to say... you four are the bravest agents I've ever known.
重点是 我之前看错你们了
The point is... I was wrong about you,
还有我希望 我有机会弥补
and I hope... there's some way I can make it right.
-给我们喷气背包吧 -我们应该亲亲
- Give us jet packs. - We should kiss.
你 你刚是不是说
Did... did you just say...
这感觉爽呆了
Well, that feels right!
我想我更喜欢喷气背包
I think I'd actually prefer a jet pack, please.
我想我们该听菜鸟的主意
I think we should go with Private's idea.
耶
Yeah!
科沃斯基 现在什么情况
Kowalski! What's our trajectory?
百分之九十五的几率着陆时会
95% certain this will end in massive...
大爆炸
flaming disaster!
-那还有百分之五呢 -无关紧要 长官
- And the other five percent? - Irrelevant, sir!
-喷气背包太棒了 -同意
- Jet packs are awesome! - Agreed!
谁说企鹅不能飞
Who says penguins can't fly?
老大 你们会把我变回正常的 是吧
Skipper, we are going to turn me back to normal, right?
当然 这是当务之急
Absolutely. First thing Monday.
-我在火箭船上 -我想要按按钮了
- I'm in a rocket ship! - I want to push the button.
-把它给我 -嘿 小偷
- Give me that! - Hey! Stealer!
-来吧 我准备好了 -好 倒数三下 一 三 走起
- Let's do this! I'm ready! - Okay, on three. One, three, go.
我只想练习一下
I'm just gonna do a little practice push.
好吧 我不会按下的
Okay, I'm not going to press it.
你干嘛拍我的手 嘿 看那儿
Why are you smacking my hand? Hey, look over there!
激光秀
I'm a laser show.
朱莉安
Julien!
现在 我们爱的小可爱菜鸟回来了 击掌
Now, that's the Private we know and love. High one!
-无敌可爱 就在面前 -欢迎回归
- Immeasurable cuteness, right there! - Good to be back.
我感觉像根法式薯条
I feel like a French fry!
-我没事 -比以前更可爱了
- I'm okay! - And with cuteness to spare!
来吧 请你们喝冷淡杯鱼汁
Come on! Frosty mugs of herring juice all around!
-菜鸟买单 -什么
- Private's buying. - What?
你知道 说实话
You know, if I'm being honest,
我还以为能更激情一点呢
I expected a little more... pizzazz!
没错 这就有激情啦
Yes! Now, that's pizzazz!